Curto, Ernest; Papers apap238
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Ernest Curto Papers
1944, 1946-1965
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Curto, Ernest, 1902-1998
apap238
17.25 cubic ft.
The Ernest Curto Papers document Curto's service in the New York State Assembly, as a representative of Niagara County (N.Y.), where he served from 1946-1964. The collection includes correspondence, subject files, and legislation from his tenure.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Ernest Curto initially donated his papers to Syracuse University in 1965. In 2006, the papers were transferred to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
New York State Assemblyman Ernest Curto was born in Pentone, Italy on July 28, 1902. In 1904, his family moved to Niagara Falls, New York, where he would later attend public schools. Curto attended the Genesee Wesleyan Preparatory Academy, and then studied at Niagara University and Syracuse University. He received his law degree from the University of Buffalo Law School, and became a member of the New York State Bar Association in 1935.
Prior to his service in the New York State Assembly, Curto was employed as research counsel for Assemblyman Harry D. Suitor. He served two terms as the acting city and police court judge for the city of Niagara Falls. Curto was also active in various labor, religious (Catholic), and community organizations.
Curto represented the Second District, which included Niagara County, in the New York State Assembly from 1946-1964. He was elected in a special election held November 6, 1945, following the death of Assemblyman Suitor. He was then re-elected in the general election of 1946. During his almost two decades in the Assembly, he had a number of committee assignments, including: Codes, Rules, Public Service, Ethics and Guidance, and Canals and Waterways. He served as the chair of the Assembly Mortgage and Real Estate Committee. Curto also participated in several joint legislative committees, including: Commerce and Economic Development, Lake Erie-Lake Ontario Canal, and Housing and Urban Redevelopment.
During his term in office, the New York State Power Authority, under the leadership of Robert Moses, constructed a massive power plant on the Niagara River. As a result of conflicts between the local governments in Niagara County and the Power Authority, Curto took a keen interest in local government matters, including taxes and land annexations. During the later part of his term, he became interested in urban renewal projects, especially in the city of Niagara Falls. Curto was also deeply concerned with labor issues, and he worked tirelessly for the passage of a bill in the Assembly that would ban the practice of employing professional strikebreakers.
Following his retirement from the Assembly in 1965, Curto returned to his private law practice, where he continued to pursue his interest in local labor and urban renewal activities. He retired in 1992. On January 6, 1998, Ernest Curto passed away after a year-long illness. He was survived by his wife, Eleanor, and his three children.
Scope and Contents
The Ernest Curto Papers span the years of 1944-1965, and are related to his career as a representative of Niagara County in the New York State Assembly. The papers include Assembly bills and supporting materials, correspondence, and subject files. These materials represent his legislative activities including legislative committee service, correspondence with constituents, organizations, and other legislators and government officials, and his sponsorship of legislation in the Assembly. The types of materials in the collection include letters, brochures, booklets, pamphlets, reports, memos, legislation, statistical data, resolutions, postcards, press clippings, press releases, speeches, hearing transcripts, notes, maps, charts, bound copies of bills, and field notes.
Researchers should note that there is a small amount of material related to his post-legislative career in the collection that dates from 1965, but as it was related to earlier materials in the collection, the archivist chose to retain it.
The series arrangement reflects the way that Curto and his staff organized and filed his papers. The archivist also elected to retain the folder titles created by Curto and his staff. The archivist chose to interfile materials that had been removed from their original folders prior to their arrival at the archives in existing series where appropriate and name them in a manner which corresponded to Curto's other folder names.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Series 1 - Subject Files, 1946-1965, Undated
Series 2 - Bills, 1956-1964, Undated
Series 3 - Legislative Correspondence, 1944, 1946-1965, Undated
Series 1 is arranged alphabetically by subject. In series 2, the bound bills are arranged chronologically, and the bill files are arranged chronologically, and then by bill introduction number. In series 3, the constituent correspondence subseries is arranged alphabetically, while the general correspondence is arranged chronologically.
Politics and Politicians; Mortgage loans--New York (State).; Political ethics--New York (State).; Politicians--New York (State).; Strikebreakers--Legal status, laws, etc.--New York (State).; Urban renewal--New York (State).; Niagara County (N.Y.).; Niagara River (N.Y. and Ont.)--Power utilization.; New York State New York (State)--Politics and government.; Bills (legislative records); Clippings; Correspondence; Files by subject; Legislative Records; Questionnaires; Reports; Resolutions; Curto, Ernest, 1902-1998.; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly.; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Committee on Canals.; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Legislative Committee on Housing and Urban Development.; New York (State). Legislature. Assembly. Committee on Ethics and Guidance.; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Committee on Commerce and Economic Development.; Power Authority of the State of New York.
- Subject Files, 1946-1965; Undated; 1; 9.2 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the general subject files of Assemblyman Ernest Curto’s office, including: letters, memos, newsletters, press releases, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, transcripts, reports, informational booklets, notes, original legislation, resolutions, petitions, resolutions, speeches, statements, maps, and constituent correspondence.
  Researchers will find that a number of these subject files have to do with Curto’s Assembly committee work and legislation. Curto served as chairman of the Assembly Mortgage and Real Estate Committee, and as such, this series contains a large volume of materials from his involvement in public hearings in 1960 and 1961 that examined the mortgage lending practices of banks across New York State. These materials include hearing transcripts and committee correspondence, as well as hundreds of surveys returned to the committee from banks and other lending institutions.
  Curto also served on the Assembly Ethics and Guidance Committee that was organized in 1961 to investigate corruption charges against then Assembly Speaker, Joseph Carlino. It was alleged that Carlino acted unethically by introducing a bill that would require all homeowners in New York State to build fallout shelters while serving as a paid board member of a company which built nuclear fallout shelters. The materials kept by Curto on this subject include hearing transcripts, correspondence, press releases, and newspaper clippings.
  Also, Curto collected a significant amount of material pertaining to the Power Authority of New York State’s work in constructing a power-generating facility on the Niagara River. Curto kept information related to federal hearings on the project, and correspondence with the Power Authority, Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation, and the City of Niagara Falls. He also kept copies of monthly progress reports and annual reports published by the Power Authority, newspaper clippings, speeches, brochures, and other materials pertaining to the project. This material dates generally from the late 1950s to the early 1960s.
  Another subject area on which Curto collected a large amount of information in the early 1960s was urban renewal. Researchers will find a number of reports and other statistical data produced by the State of New York, as well as correspondence, maps, memos, and other materials related to urban renewal and urban development projects.
  Researchers should note that this series contains information related to legislation that Curto introduced that banned the practice of hiring professional strikebreakers in New York State. Curto maintained information on this subject in the subject files and also in the bills series, so researchers interested in the subject should examine the materials held in both places.
  - Adult Education, 1960 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - AFL-CIO, 1962; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2-3)
  - AFL-CIO, 1963; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4-5)
  - AFL-CIO, 1964; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6-7)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, 1961; 1963-1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, 18 to 21 years, correspondence, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9-10)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control Law, Moreland Commission Study and Reports, 1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11-12)
  - All-American Canal, 1960; 1962-1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Appointment Calendar, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Assembly Information Booklets, 1957; 1959-1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Bingo, 1957; 1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Bingo, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Bingo, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Biography, Ernest Curto (School Children Requests), 1963; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Capital Construction, 1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Civil Practice Law and Rules Reports, 1962; 1964 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Public Hearing, Albany, 1959 March 04 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Public Hearing, New York City, 1959 November 30 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Public Hearing, Buffalo (part 1 of 2), 1960 October 05 (Box 1 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Public Hearing, Buffalo (part 2 of 2), 1960 October 05 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Public Hearing, Buffalo, 1961 August 08 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2-3)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Public Hearing, Albany, 1963 February 13 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4-5)
  - Commerce and Economic Development Committee- Report, 1959 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Committee Membership Lists, 1962 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Consumer Protection, 1964 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Department of Commerce Reports, 1964 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Education Funding, 1960 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee, 1959; 1961; 1964; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee, 1957; 1961-1962; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee, 1961-1962; 1964; Undated (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany, 1962 January 02 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14-15)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, New York City, 1962 January 04 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, New York City, 1962 January 05 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17-18)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, New York City, 1962 January 12 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, New York City, 1962 January 15 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany, 1962 January 16 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, New York City, 1962 January 19 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22-23)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany, 1962 January 22 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany, 1962 January 23 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany (folders 1 and 2 of 3), 1962 February 01 (Box 2 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26-27)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany (folders 3 of 3), 1962 February 01 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, Albany, 1962 February 02 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2-4)
  - Ethics and Guidance Committee- Hearing, New York City, 1962 February 05 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5-6)
  - Ethics Code Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Family Court, 1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Field Notes and Supporting Materials, 1959-1961; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Firearms, Sale of (Completed), 1960 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Firearms, Sale of (Completed), 1963-1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Firearms- State Commission of Investigation Report, 1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Full Crew Law, 1963-1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Full Crew Law, 1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Highways, 1960; 1963-1964; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Highways, 1963-1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Home Rule Requests, 1960; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Hospital Legislation, 1963; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Hospitals- Governor's Proposal to Exempt Non-Profits, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19-20)
  - Korean War Veterans Bonus- Correspondence, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Labor (Completed), 1962-1963; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Labor (Completed), 1963; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Labor- General, 1960; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Labor (Pending), 1964; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Labor- Public Employees, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Labor- Public Employees, 1964 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Labor Reports, 1962; 1964; Undated (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Labor- Unemployment Insurance, 1963 (Box 3 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Labor- Unemployment Insurance, 1963-1964; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Labor- Workmen's Compensation, 1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Law Revision Commission, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Law Revision Commission, 1963 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Liquor License Fees, 1963 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Liquor Proposals, 1964; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6-7)
  - Liquor- Tax-Duty Free Sales, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Lists (Pending), 1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Local Government-Commission on Per Capita Aid Report, 1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10-11)
  - Local Government-State Aid, 1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Local Government-Tax System Report, 1958 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Local Government-Town Board Duties and Powers, 1959 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Milk Legislation Correspondence, 1963; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Clerk's Report, 1964 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Expenses, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee-Federal Government Correspondence, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Final Report of Bills, 1963 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- General Committee Information, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- General Correspondence, 1960; 1963; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Geographical Patterns of Mortgage Lending Report, 1960 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22-23)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Housing Statistics, 1958; 1960; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Nevada State Report on Incidental Charges, 1959; 1963 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Nevada State Report on Incidental Charges, 1962 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Notes, Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Press Coverage, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Processing Brokers Lists, 1961 (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Public Hearing, Buffalo, 1960 November 15; 1960; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 30-31)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Public Hearing, New York City, 1960 December 20; 1960; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 32-33)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Public Hearing, Albany, 1961 January 17; 1960-1961; Undated (Box 4 (1-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Public Hearing, Albany, 1961 January 17 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Reports, 1961 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Request for Copies of the Report, 1961 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Resolutions, Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Savings Bank Association Report, 1960 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Surveys, New York City, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6-8)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Surveys, Not Dealing in Mortgages, 1960; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Surveys, Out of State, 1960; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Surveys, Public Hearing Attendees, 1960-1961; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Mortgage and Real Estate Committee- Surveys, Upstate New York, 1960; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12-16)
  - Municipal Law Seminar, 1962 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Municipal Law Seminar, 1962-1963 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings for Curto Legislation and Committee Work, 1961-1962; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - New York City Bar Association- Legislative Bulletins, 1961; 1964 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - New York City Bar Association- Legislative Bulletins, 1964 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Niagara Falls Board of Harbor Commissioners Meeting, 1946 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Niagara Frontier State Park, 1949; 1963-1964 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Niagara Frontier State Park- Map, Undated (Oversized 1, Folder 6)
  - Niagara International Music Festival Preliminary Study, 1963 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Niagara Project- Army Corps of Engineers, 1952; 1955 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Niagara Project- Basic Industries Committee, 1957; 1962 (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Niagara Project- City of Niagara Falls, 1957; 1960-1961; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Niagara Project- Data and Statistics, 1959-1960; Undated (Box 5 (1-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Niagara Project-Federal Power Commission Application, 1956 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Niagara Project-Federal Power Commission Hearing, 1957 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Niagara Project-General Correspondence, 1951; 1953; 1955-1958; 1961; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Niagara Project-Legal Opinions for the Power Authority, 1955; 1959 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Niagara Project-Legislative Materials, 1951; 1956-1958; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Niagara Project- Notes, Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Correspondence, 1954-1957 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Correspondence, 1957-1958; 1961-1962 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Correspondence, 1962-1963; Undated (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1953 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1954 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 11-12)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1955 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1956 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1957 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 15-17)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1958 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18-20)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1959 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21-23)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1960 (Box 6 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24-26)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1961 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 1-2)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1962 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1963 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Niagara Project- Power Authority Reports, 1964 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Niagara Project- Press Coverage, 1951-1965; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 6-7)
  - Niagara Project- Press Releases, 1951; 1954-1955; 1957-1958; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Niagara Project- Public Works Committee, Senate Hearings, 1953 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Niagara Project- Public Works Committee, Senate Hearings, 1954 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 10-11)
  - Niagara Project- Public Works Committee, U.S. Senate, 1951; 1953-1955 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Niagara Project- Reports (Charts), 1964 (Oversized 1, Folder 1)
  - Niagara Project- Reports and Brochures, 1947-1963; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 13-15)
  - Niagara Project- Report on Resolutions and Editorials, 1955 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Niagara Project- Resolutions, 1951; 1953; 1955; 1957; 1960 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Niagara Project- Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation, 1955; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 18-19)
  - Niagara Project- Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation, 1956 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Niagara Project- Rochester Gas and Electric Corporation, 1957; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Niagara Project- Souvenir Journal from Carpenters Convention, 1961 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Niagara Project- Speeches, 1955; 1957; 1961; Undated (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Niagara Project- State Joint Legislative Committee to Study Assessment and Taxation, 1956-1957 (Box 7 (1-Subject Files), Folder 24)